Guide to the Central Washington University Office of Business and Financial Affairs, Vice President’s Files 1961-2002
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Office of Business and Financial Affairs, Vice President’s Files
1961-2002
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG068-06-77
Central Washington University, Office of Business and Financial Affairs
8.0 cubic feet 16 letter sized document cases Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, policies, and procedures in good condition
This collection consists of correspondence, memorandums and reports received by the Vice President of Business and Financial Affairs at Central Washington University from 1961 to 2002.
Historical Note
The Office of Business and Financial Affairs at Central Washington University was established in 1970 as a division of the Business Office. From 1933 to 1969, business and financial duties were administered by the Business Manager. Prior to 1933, the school hired an accountant to supervise the financial activities of the institution.
The files of the Vice President contain committee minutes, policy and procedures, plans, budget proposals and other legal and financial documents related to the management of Central Washington University. Included in the files are audit reports, Budget Advisory Committee minutes, Budget Planning Committee minutes, Capital Project reports, Housing and Dining Services projections, memoranda from various inter-institutional committees, correspondence from the Washington State Office of Financial Management, Operating Budgets developed by the university and records on labor discussions and disputes.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Arranged alphabetically by title of subject.
Open to the public for educational research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University. Office of Business and Financial Affairs
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History; Financial records
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Budget--Washington (State)
College administrators--United States
- 1997-1999 Budget Requests, 1996 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Acquisition Plan for a Digital Equipment Corporation, 1983 (Box-folder 1-2)
- ADA Affairs – Special Report, 1997 (Box-folder 1-3)
- ADA Capital Funds Request, 1993 (Box-folder 1-4)
- ADA Capital Funds Request, 1999 (Box-folder 1-5)
- ADA Compliancy, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1-6)
- ADA Self-evaluation, 1993 (Box-folder 1-7)
- ADA Transition Plan, 1992 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Administrative Salary Committee, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Administrative Salary Information, 1976-1992 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Admissions: A plan for the Future, 1972 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Affirmative Action Plan, 1997 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Animal Research Facility, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Annual Financial Report, 1986 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Annual Leave Policy, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Alumni Association, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Applicants, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 2-5)
- Asbestos Management – Psychology Building, 1988 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Art in Public Places Guidelines, 1984-1994 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Arts Acquisition Policy, 1980 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Audit Report – CWU Associated Students, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Audit Report – CWU Associated Students, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Audit Report – CWU Associated Students, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Audit Report – CWU Associated Students, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 2-12)
- Audit Report – CWU Associated Students, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Audit Report – CWU Associated Students Fund, 1998 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Audit Report – CWU, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Audit Report – CWU, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Audit Report – CWU, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2-17)
- Audit Report – Housing and Food Services, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2-18)
- Audit Report – Housing and Food Services, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2-19)
- Audit Report – Housing and Food Services, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Audit Report – Housing and Food Services, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 2-21)
- Audit Report – Housing and Food Services, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 2-22)
- Audit Report – Housing and Food Services, 1998 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Auxiliary Services – Parking Lot Research Findings, 1987 (Box-folder 2-24)
- Bicycle Path Committee, 1988 (Box-folder 3-1)
- Board of Trustees Motion Index, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 3-2)
- Board of Trustees Motion Index, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 3-3)
- Board of Trustees Motion Index, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 3-4)
- Buckley Amendment, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 3-5)
- Budget – Board of Trustees, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 3-6)
- Budget – Board of Trustees, 1975 (Box-folder 3-7)
- Budget – Board of Trustees, 1975 (Box-folder 3-8)
- Budget Advisory Committee, 1975 (Box-folder 3-9)
- Budget Advisory Committee, 1977 (Box-folder 4-1)
- Budget Advisory Committee Minutes, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 4-2)
- Budget Advisory Committee Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 4-3)
- Budget Advisory Committee Minutes, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 4-4)
- Budget Committee, 1972 (Box-folder 4-5)
- Budget Committee – Correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 4-6)
- Budget Committee Meeting agendas, 1973 (Box-folder 4-7)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes, 1973 (Box-folder 4-8)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes and agendas, 1973 (Box-folder 4-9)
- Budget Committee Meeting agendas, 1974 (Box-folder 4-10)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 4-11)
- Budget Committee – Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 5-1)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes, 1975 (Box-folder 5-2)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes and agendas, 1975 (Box-folder 5-3)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes and correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 5-4)
- Budget Committee Meeting minutes and correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 5-5)
- Budget guide, 1973 (Box-folder 5-6)
- Budget Planning Committee – Correspondence, 1970 (Box-folder 5-7)
- Budget Planning Committee minutes and agendas, 1970 (Box-folder 5-8)
- Budget Planning Committee, 1971 (Box-folder 5-9)
- Budget request, 1994 (Box-folder 5-10)
- Buildings and grounds, 1996 (Box-folder 6-1)
- C. P. E. reports, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6-2)
- CWSC Foundation, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 6-3)
- Campus Climate, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 6-4)
- Campus Gift Policy, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 6-5)
- Capital Budget Request, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 6-6)
- Capital Budget Committee, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 6-7)
- Capital Needs of CSCW: The 1969-1971 Biennium and the next decade, 1968 (Box-folder 6-8)
- Capital Policy / Communications Committee, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 6-9)
- Capital Projects, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 6-10)
- Capital Projects, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 6-11)
- Capital Projects, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 6-12)
- Capital Projects, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 6-13)
- Capital Projects, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 6-14)
- Capital Projects, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 7-1)
- Capital Projects Reports, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 7-2)
- Career Development Services Employment Report, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 7-3)
- Collective Bargaining – Washington Federation of State Employees, 1970 (Box-folder 7-4)
- College Logo, 1977 (Box-folder 7-5)
- Commercial Activities Policy, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7-6)
- Commercial Signage on Campus, 1987 (Box-folder 7-7)
- Compulsory on-campus residency requirement (under 21 years of age), 1978 (Box-folder 7-8)
- Computing and Telecommunication Services – Using the Internet, 1994 (Box-folder 7-9)
- Computer Facilities Use Policy, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 7-10)
- Conflict of Interest Regulations, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 7-11)
- Constitution and By-laws of the CWSC Trustees (Box-folder 7-12)
- Cost Recovery Study, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 7-13)
- Cost Recovery Study, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 7-14)
- Council of Higher Education Cost Study, 1975 (Box-folder 7-15)
- Council for Postsecondary Education, 1976 (Box-folder 7-16)
- Council for Postsecondary Education, 1977 (Box-folder 7-17)
- Council for Postsecondary Education, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 7-18)
- Council of Presidents, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 7-19)
- Council of Presidents, 1983-1993 (Box-folder 8-1)
- CWU Insurance Summary, 1965, 1985 (Box-folder 8-2)
- Data Processing Authority, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 8-3)
- Development Reports, 2001 (Box-folder 8-4)
- Disaster Plan, 1979 (Box-folder 8-5)
- Disaster Planning – Bomb threats and student disruptions, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 8-6)
- Disruptive Demonstration Policies, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 8-7)
- Discussion / Analysis of Faculty Salary Issue – Draft, 1999 (Box-folder 8-8)
- Division Mission Statement and Strategic Plan, 1993 (Box-folder 8-9)
- Dog Policy, 1972 (Box-folder 8-10)
- Drug Abuse Prevention Program Education and Referral Report, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 8-11)
- Edison Hall – Report and Recommendations, 1964-1985 (Box-folder 8-12)
- Edmond Community College, 2002 (Box-folder 8-13)
- Efficiency and Productivity, 1987 (Box-folder 8-14)
- Emergency Closure Policy, 1973-1992 (Box-folder 8-15)
- Emergency Closure Plans due to weather conditions and fuel shortages, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 8-16)
- Emergency Preparedness Plan, 1999 (Box-folder 8-17)
- Energy Conservation Plan, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 9-1)
- Executive orders, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 9-2)
- Executive orders, 1985-1995 (Box-folder 9-3)
- Exempt Employee Codes, 1996 (Box-folder 9-4)
- Facilities Use Policy, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 9-5)
- Faculty Workloads in Washington, 1972 (Box-folder 9-6)
- Financial Aid – Students, 1971-1988 (Box-folder 9-7)
- Financial Report, 1988 (Box-folder 9-8)
- Fire Protection, 1992 (Box-folder 9-9)
- Firearms Policy, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 9-10)
- General memos issued by Vice President of Business and Financial Affairs, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 9-11)
- General operating procedures for bomb threats, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 9-12)
- Gift Policy, 1980 (Box-folder 10-1)
- Grievance Procedure, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 10-2)
- Highline Community College, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 10-3)
- Higher Education Computing Consortium Board, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 10-4)
- Higher Education Coordinating Board, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 10-5)
- Hiring freeze – Executive order, 1980 (Box-folder 10-6)
- History of Faculty Retirement System, 1939-1975 (Box-folder 10-7)
- History of the CWU Control and Monitoring System, 1985 (Box-folder 10-8)
- Housing and Dining Services Projections, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 10-9)
- Housing and Dining Services Projections, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 10-10)
- Housing and Dining Services Projections, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 10-11)
- Housing and Dining Services Projections, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 10-12)
- Housing and Dining Services Projections, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 10-13)
- Information Systems Risk Assessment Program, 1998 (Box-folder 11-1)
- Inter-institutional Subcommittee of Internal Auditors, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 11-2)
- Inter-institutional Committee of Business Officers, 1974 (Box-folder 11-3)
- Inter-institutional Committee of Business Officers, 1975 (Box-folder 11-4)
- Inter-institutional Committee of Space Officers, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 11-5)
- Inter-institutional Committee of Space Officers, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 11-6)
- Instructional Expenditures per student in Washington, 1972 (Box-folder 11-7)
- KCAT – FCC compliancy, 1995 (Box-folder 11-8)
- Key Policy, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 11-9)
- Layoff Procedure, 1970 (Box-folder 11-10)
- Legislative Budget Committee, 1974-1989 (Box-folder 11-11)
- Liquor on campus, 1969-1992 (Box-folder 12-1)
- Long Range Capital Investment, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 12-2)
- Mary Mathewson Estate, 1988 (Box-folder 12-3)
- Miscellaneous University Policies and Procedures, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 12-4)
- Mount St. Helens – Executive Order, 1980 (Box-folder 12-5)
- NCATE Institutional Report – Center for Teaching and Learning, 1998 (Box-folder 12-6)
- Negotiated agreement between CWSC Federation of Teachers and Board of Trustees of CWSC, 1977 (Box-folder 12-7)
- Noel-Levitz Student Satisfaction Inventory, 1997 (Box-folder 12-8)
- Nicholson Pavilion Addition Committee Report, 1986 (Box-folder 12-9)
- Office of Financial Management, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 12-10)
- Office of Financial Management, 1979 (Box-folder 12-11)
- Office of Financial Management, 1980 (Box-folder 12-12)
- Office of Financial Management, 1981 (Box-folder 12-13)
- Office of Financial Management, 1982 (Box-folder 12-14)
- Office of Financial Management, 1983 (Box-folder 12-15)
- Office of Financial Management, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 12-16)
- Office of Financial Management, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 13-1)
- Office of Financial Management, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 13-2)
- Office of Financial Management, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 13-3)
- Office of Resident Living Annual Report, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 13-4)
- Old Hospital Usage, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 13-5)
- Operating Budget, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 13-6)
- Operating Budget, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 13-7)
- Operating Budget, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 13-8)
- Operating Budget, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 13-9)
- Operating Budget, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 13-10)
- Operating Budget, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 14-1)
- Opinions and perceptions of different constituencies connected to CWU, 1993 (Box-folder 14-2)
- Parking Plan, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 14-3)
- Petitions from distance centers requesting representation in student government, 1999 (Box-folder 14-4)
- Policies and procedures in event of seriously disruptive demonstrations or disorders on campus, 1970 (Box-folder 14-5)
- Productivity Program, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 14-6)
- Proposal to develop an integrated marketing program, 2002 (Box-folder 14-7)
- Provost’s Accountability Report, 1997 (Box-folder 14-8)
- Railroad corridor master plan, 1986 (Box-folder 14-9)
- Recharge and physical plant work force information, 1977 (Box-folder 14-10)
- Records Management, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 14-11)
- Reimbursement procedures for moving and meals, 1976-1990 (Box-folder 14-12)
- Report of results of comprehensive research project: Surveys of Washington high school students and parents, etc., 2001 (Box-folder 14-13)
- Strategic Planning Process and Assumption Response, 1992 (Box-folder 14-14)
- Strike Contingency Plan, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 14-15)
- Report of the Commercial Activities Review Committee (Box-folder 15-1)
- Retirement Rules and Regulations, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 15-2)
- Revenue Dedication, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 15-3)
- Revised Higher Education Facilities Inventory and Classification Manual, 1991 (Box-folder 15-4)
- Selling on Campus Policy, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 15-5)
- Services and Activities Committee and Guidelines, 1994 (Box-folder 15-6)
- Sexual Harassment Policy, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15-7)
- Skateboard Policy, 1988 (Box-folder 15-8)
- State Funded Student Definition, 1994 (Box-folder 15-9)
- State Funds for Entertainment, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 15-10)
- Strike Contingency Plan, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 15-11)
- Student Compensation Study, 1980 (Box-folder 15-12)
- Student Required to Live in College Residence Halls, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 15-13)
- Student Rights and Responsibilities, 1984 (Box-folder 15-14)
- Student Wages, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15-15)
- Surveys of Washington High School Students and Parents, Influences and Potential Adult Students, 2001 (Box-folder 15-16)
- Suspended Operations Policy for Classified Staff, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 15-17)
- Task Force on Budget Strategy, 1981 (Box-folder 16-1)
- Tax Roll Back, 1993 (Box-folder 16-2)
- Temporary Employment, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 16-3)
- Traffic Regulations, 1970 (Box-folder 16-4)
- Tuition Refunds, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 16-5)
- Union matters and election, 1974 (Box-folder 16-6)
- University Facilities Analysis, 1994 (Box-folder 16-7)
- University Structure / Organization, 1996 (Box-folder 16-8)
- University Wide Goals Statement and Strategy Plan (Box-folder 16-9)
- Use of University Facilities by Faculty Publications Policy, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 16-10)
- Vacation Leave, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 16-11)
- Vending Machines Operation, 1990 (Box-folder 16-12)
- Whistleblower Act, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 16-13)
- Women’s Resource Center Productivity and Activity Report, 1996 (Box-folder 16-14)
- Work Study Personnel Policy, 1973 (Box-folder 16-15)
- Y2K, 1999 (Box-folder 16-16)
- Yakima Firing Center Expansion, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 16-17)